Guide to the Campbell-Mumford Papers 1719-1980 (Bulk 1793-1892) MS 98
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series IV: Printed Materials
  - Subseries 1: Publications
    - "Majority Report of Commissioners of Land Transfer", 1885 (Box 22)
    - The History of Cowal, 1908 (Box 22)
    - Publications of the Scottish History Society: Third Series, Volume XXII: Highland Papers, Volume IV, 1934 (Box 22)
  - Subseries 2: Clippings
    Arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - 121st Regiment - N.Y. Volunteers, 1877-1879, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Cherry Valley Massacre Monument, 1877-1878 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Cherry Valley - General Materials, 1876-1945, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Isaac Jackson of Union College Tribute, 1876 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Native Americans - General Materials, 1881-1887, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Obituaries, 1862-1865 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Union College - General Materials, 1882-1883, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Series V: Non-Campbell and Non-Mumford Family Materials
  This series spans a wide range of dates (1703-1847) and a commensurately wide range of subject matter, mostly in English, but also in French. Types of material range from correspondence to military reports, commissions to depositions. Notable materials include a letter from Aaron Burr, a deposition regarding General Thomas Gage, and a quotation copied by Thomas F. Marshall.
  - Revolutionary War Materials, deeds, commissions, oaths, assembly minutes, petitions, military reports, correspondence, and other writings, 1719-1847 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, depositions, Latin quotation, 1703-1837 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Series VI: 1980 Supplement
  This series hinges on the Campbell family's participation in the Civil War, especially the service given by Douglas Campbell 1st and Cleaveland Campbell and by the 121st and 152nd New York Volunteers. Lewis Campbell and William Campbell also figure prominently in the series. Other material includes correspondence of Douglas Campbell 1st about his monograph on the Puritans and a list of survivors of the Cherry Valley Massacre. Materials is arranged chronologically.
  - Campbell Family Materials: slave purchase receipts, pension claims, and other legal documents, 1764-1844 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Cherry Valley Massacre Escapees, 1778 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Cleaveland Campbell Correspondence and Related Civil War Materials, 1861-1864 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Lewis Campbell and Related Civil War Correspondence, 1861-1864 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Orders, 1861-1864 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - William W. Campbell Correspondence, 1861-1879 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Enlistment Materials, 1862 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Passes, 1862-1863 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Abstract of Materials Expended or Consumed, 1863 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - List of Articles Lost or Destroyed, 1863 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Statement of Charges on Muster and Pay Rolls, 1863 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Charges and Courts Martial Materials, 1863-1864 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Lambert Hensler Materials, 1863-1864 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - List of Ordnance Received, 1863-1864 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - List of Ordnance Transferred, 1863-1864 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Monthly Return of Equipage, 1863-1864 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Unserviceable Ordnance Stores, 1863-1864 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1878-1881 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Douglas Campbell 1st Correspondence and Related Materials, 1886-1892 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Clothing Receipts, 1863-1864 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Muster Rolls, 1863-1864 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Quarterly Return of Ordnance and Ordnance Stores, 1862-1864 (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Series VII: Newspapers and Periodicals
  This series features newspaper clippings and periodicals from New Jersey and New York State. They range from obituary notices to reprints of Douglas Campbell 1st's lectures and speeches, from accounts of the 121st New York Volunteers and Emory Upton to accounts of the Cherry Valley Massacre Memorial, from news of the establishment of the New York Soldiers' Home to book advertisements for Douglas Campbell's work on the Puritans. The materials are arranged alphabetically.
  - Cape May County Gazette, 1886 January 30 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Albany Law Journal, 1877 October 6 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Bath Newspaper Clippings, 1877 March 7; 1877 June 15 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Cherry Valley Gazette, 1876 July 13; 1876 July 27; 1893 March 16 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Cooperstown Newspaper Clippings, 1843 May 1; 1877 August 16; 1878 October 10; 1886 January 27 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - New York City Newspaper Clippings, 1880 January 11; 1893 March 16; 1893 March 18 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Schenectady Newspaper Clippings, 1836 January 8; 1864 June 30 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Troy Daily Whig, 1846 February 27 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Waverly Advocate, 1876 June 9; 1876 July 21 (Box 26, Folder 12)